ADAPTED FROM
THE LEGEND OF KUNSHAN JADE BY TAN TIANYIN
-Come on. Greet our guest.
-Okay.
No need.
Wuyi, how are you doing?
Zijing.
You look thin.
-Mr. Yuchi.
-Duanwu.
No, I should call you Ms. Su now.
Mr. Yuchi, you are well informed.
You're famous in Yangzhou.
I asked around.
Many people showed me the way.
I'm flattered.
You started from scratch in Yangzhou
and achieved so much.
Your looks and abilities
are outstanding and remarkable.
My Clear Mind is nothing compared
to your Langhuan Dockyard.
It's just a small business.
I was just lucky.
Mr. Yuchi, let me introduce them to you.
This is Yunxiu,
the Master Artisan of Clear Mind.
Mr. Yuchi, nice to meet you.
They are my right-hand men.
I am Yingtao. He is Gaoshou.
He's my subordinate.
-This is Mr. Zhang.
-Mr. Zhang, we know each other.
You know each other?
Mr. Zhang was anxious
after you were attacked.
He came to me to look for you.
Mr. Yuchi, how are you?
We were anxious to find them
at Langhuan Dockyard.
We meet again today.
When I first arrived in Yangzhou,
I heard that there was a fair
and impartial inspector.
It must be you.
I'm flattered.
-Let's sit down and talk.
-Okay.
-Please.
-Please, Mr. Yuchi.
Okay.
This way.
Please.
Have a seat.
Mr. Yuchi.
-Taste the tea in Yangzhou.
-Okay.
Have you ever been to Yangzhou before?
It's much better than desert tea.
I didn't expect you
to be able to start Clear Mind
from scratch after such a big event.
And you're doing great.
If your father and mother see this
above there, they will be happy.
If my father and mother
see this above there,
they will be happy.
Wuyi.
Why did you come to Yangzhou?
There's a lot you don't know.
I am no longer the owner
of Langhuan Dockyard.
I was anxious
when you were attacked
at Langhuan Dockyard.
I looked for you many times,
but I couldn't find you.
I felt hopeless.
Later,
officers came to me many times.
Everyone at Langhuan Dockyard
was in a panic.
So, I decided to quit.
Wouldn't it be better
to come to the southeast
to enjoy the mountains and rivers?
So were we.
We've been through a lot
to get settled in Yangzhou.
I'm here to see you.
As the host,
you should take good care of me.
Don't worry.
I've arranged everything for you.
Great.
Come on.
I heard Clear Mind is famous
for its glassware.
Here's a Persian glass bracelet for you.
Mr. Yuchi.
It's an expensive gift.
Good things should be given to people
who understand them.
Since Wuyi wanted to give it to you,
just take it.
Okay, I'll take it.
Thank you, Mr. Yuchi.
What are you going to do to thank me?
I will take you on a tour
of Yangzhou. What do you say?
Great.
You've been working hard lately.
Let's close our shop today and go out.
We can go out.
-We can go out.
-Great.
-Gaoshou.
-Don't be rude.
Mr. Zhang.
Come with us if you're not busy.
Mr. Zhang has something important to do.
I don't think he has time.
I don't have important things to do today.
If you, an official,
socialize too much with businessmen,
people will start talking.
As the saying goes,
"A clean hand wants no washing."
Mr. Yuchi.
Please.
Let's go.
You don't have to go.
I'll take you on a good tour of Yangzhou.
Thank you.
Mr. Yuchi.
This is the view of Jiangnan.
It should be different from the desert.
If the world's beautiful scenery is three,
Yangzhou occupies two shares.
Watch singing and dancing
on the bridge under the moon.
There are streets and water but no horses.
-Please.
-This way.
Ms. Su.
I heard that there are painters
in Yangzhou
who can paint people very similar.
Let's go to them and paint
a painting of us.
Where can we find them?
Mr. Zhang, you can paint, right?
I can't do it.
I want to be in the painting.
We want to paint a painting
of Clear Mind's people.
Mr. Yan is not from Clear Mind.
What does it have to do with you?
You have a thick skin.
Let me see how the Go skills
of the Central Plains people are.
Let's go.
You like it, too, right?
The game is set.
Black is going to lose.
Good.
Tang's Go pieces are pottery.
They're rough.
And they don't sound good.
That's why I lost.
Where are my Go pieces?
Look.
They are jade pieces.
-Each one is a one-of-a-kind treasure.
-Jade pieces?
They are rare in Yangzhou
and even in Tang.
Can I have a look?
They are national treasures of Haidong.
They are all unique.
Unique.
What are you thinking about?
They are good pieces.
Let's have another game with your pieces.
You must have thought
-of a money-making business.
-Let's have another game.
Yunxiu.
Come here.
Do you remember
when we made black glass?
Yes.
What's the use of it?
No wonder she's a shopkeeper.
She thinks about business all the time.
She was born to be a businesswoman.
You have a good eye for business.
You can find business opportunities
everywhere.
Duanwu.
The colors and materials
are easy to handle.
But it's difficult
to make them the same size.
It is difficult
Duanwu, why don't we try
using the mold casting process?
We can make a wax piece first.
Then, make a mold with it.
Next, pour the melted glass into it.
Finally, cut it and flatten it
while it's hot.
We can give it a try.
The ratio of materials must be accurate.
-You have to be very careful.
-More.
Ready to open to the kiln.
Yingtao, get ready.
Enough.
Okay.
Be careful. Wait for it to cool down.
Mr. Qin, please take a look.
This is a finished product.
Good.
Nice texture.
Yangzhou is famous for having treasures
from all over the world.
Playing Go is an elegant thing.
But there are no merchants in Yangzhou
who can make good Go pieces.
Miss, your Go pieces are nice.
Ladies,
Your pieces look good
and crystal clear.
Where did you get them?
What's this made of?
Is it made of crystal?
It's rare.
When you look up at it,
it looks like jasper.
When you look down at it,
it looks like black paint.
It's impossible.
These are Clear Mind's original glass
Go pieces.
Your pieces are made of glass?
Can your glass pieces
match my jade pieces?
They can't match your jade pieces.
Glass pieces feel smooth
and sound clear.
Each one has a different pattern on it.
It's so special.
More importantly,
they show different colors
in different weather.
That's true.
Such good Go pieces
only cost 100,000 mace.
What?
-One hundred thousand mace?
-It's cheap.
After listening to you,
I want to buy it.
Where did you say you bought it?
-Clear Mind.
-Where?
Clear Mind.
-Clear Mind?
I'm interested.
I'll buy one.
-Sir, wait.
-Let's go together.
I have a list for ordering.
Do you mean I can order from you?
-Yes.
-I'll order one.
-Me too.
-I'll have one.
Don't rush.
Clear Mind makes them every day.
You can order as much as you want.
Pay a deposit of 10,000 mace
and you can get one at Clear Mind.
It's cheap.
-I want one.
-Don't rush. Come on.
Everybody will have it.
Don't rush.
-You can order as much as you want.
-I want one.
Everybody will have it.
Lady Shijiu, we're out of stock.
Let's stock up.
If you're tired, get some rest.
-I'll do the chores.
-Is there anyone here?
Is there anyone here?
We're not selling anymore.
We are not here to buy things.
We are just looking around.
We have no goods.
What do you want to look at?
There's nothing in your shop.
Are you for sale?
What are you talking about?
We're leaving.
-You can't come in here!
-Out of the way!
We're closed today!
Let go.
-Let me touch you. Let me touch you.
-Let go!
-What do you want?
-Let's go!
-Let go!
-What do you want?
-Let's go.
Stop! Give it back!
You evil guys!
-Let go!
-Don't take my money!
-What are you talking about?
-Give me my money back!
-Stop!
-It's ours!
-What's wrong, Ms. Su?
-Give it to me!
Don't leave!
-Give it back!
-Stop!
Let go! Get out of here!
-Don't leave!
-Stop!
-Scum! How can you bully girls?
Shame on you!
You're evil!
-We'll see!
-I dare you to come again!
Get out of here!
You went through a lot
to get Zhenlang Pavilion back,
but you make it like that.
You did whatever it took
to get it back.
Since you're alive,
you should move on…
and live well.
Let's go.
Prince Ying
is about to arrive in Yangzhou.
Are you going to meet him like this?
Su Muzhe is too hateful.
I want her dead.
Did you forget Prince Ying's order?
Don't act rashly.
But I can't put up with it.
Help me.
When you get it done,
I'll give you
the Jubao House's Chengnan branch.
Aren't you afraid
that Prince Ying will blame you?
Prince Ying wanted to come here
because of Yan Zijing and Su Muzhe.
His purpose should be the same as mine.
I'm not interested
in your Chengnan branch.
What I want is in Su Muzhe's hands.
If you kill her, you'll get what you want.
Okay.
I promise you.
I heard that Clear Mind
has three branches to open.
-Please go in.
-Really?
Let's have a look.
-Have a look.
-Their business is good.
-There's a long line again.
-Yeah.
So many people.
-Miss, come and have a look.
-Slow down.
Miss, have a look.
Look.
This is our new glass hairpin.
-Please sign here.
-Okay.
-I want one.
-It's really lively.
-Have you heard it?
-Come on.
They're opening branches.
I heard. She's amazing.
Glass pieces are nice and cheap.
-That's true.
-I want one, too.
-Let's buy some.
-Go.
Write more clearly.
Please sign here. Thank you.
Excuse me.
Ms. Su. Mr. Kang is here.
-Come on.
-I got it.
-Wait a moment.
-Okay.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I didn't greet you.
Mr. Kang, why didn't you inform me
before you came?
I heard Clear Mind's new glass pieces
are nice and cheap.
Ms. Su.
Can you show me?
Mr. Kang, I didn't expect you
to be interested in it.
-Wait a minute.
-It's delicate.
Thank you.
-Mr. Kang, here you are.
-Take care.
Do you like it?
Here you are.
-It's beautiful.
-Okay.
-Have a look.
-Is this the only one?
I want a thousand sets
to be delivered in a month.
One month?
If I take your order,
I'll have to delay
the previous customer's orders.
Clear Mind will lose credit.
If you want 1,000 sets,
I think it will take us
more than three months.
No, more than three months.
Can you wait for more than three months?
If you can't,
we'll work together next time.
It's a big order.
Aren't you worried about offending me?
I'm worried,
but Clear Mind is a small shop.
We value credit.
If you just said yes,
that's our last deal.
I'll give you three months.
I'll send someone to pick them up
in three months.
Mr. Kang, I'll get a contract for you.
Okay.
Thank you.
Gaoshou, take it easy.
Don't tremble your mouth.
-I'm not.
-Don't tremble your mouth.
Don't be nervous.
Yingtao, your left eyebrow. No.
Your right eyebrow.
Lower your right eyebrow a little bit.
Lower. Lift the left corner of your mouth.
No, right corner.
It's good.
Don't be nervous, you two.
I'm not nervous.
-Look here.
-Duanwu, we're here.
-Do your clothes fit?
-Yes.
-Let me see.
-Mr. Qin.
-It fits you well.
-No.
It's good.
-Come on.
-What are you painting?
Come here.
-It fits you well.
-I have one more…
-It's good.
-It's okay. We'll talk about it later.
Supervisor Kang, come on.
-Coming.
-It's not over yet.
I'm not playing with you.
I want to paint a portrait.
Won't you join us?
I won't join you.
All right.
Come on.
Am I late?
You're just in time.
Supervisor Kang.
It will take two hours.
Find a place to sit.
Come here.
Otherwise, your legs…
My legs? Okay.
I have the best legs in the West Regions.
-Be careful.
-It's good.
Your intimacy. It's good.
Stand still.
Is everyone here?
Let's get started.
-Here.
-We're all here.
Come on.
I still have work to do.
Mr. Qin can't hold back anymore.
Yingtao.
Is that your double chin?
Yunxiu, I told you he painted me fat.
No. It's beautiful.
-Yeah. Your teeth are white.
-Really?
Gaoshou.
Why didn't you look at the Yingtao?
-I…
-I wanted to ignore him.
I wanted to pretend to be deep.
I have a question.
Am I usually so handsome?
Supervisor Kang's head is tilted.
I didn't even notice it.
His head was tilted the whole time.
You're not as handsome as Du Ming.
Wait. Look at Zhang Jinran.
He doesn't look like an official.
Mr. Zhang's head is as thick as his head.
Ms. Su is beautiful.
Duanwu is so beautiful.
-The painting looks exactly like her.
-You and him are a good match.
No, the painting is nice.
I'll go to that painter
and paint a portrait for myself.
-Supervisor Kang, are you addicted?
-Good.
It's beautiful.
Supervisor Kang,
you're whiter in the painting.
Supervisor Kang.
Your legs are not good. Walk slowly.
-Walk slowly.
-Don't fall again.
You're on crutches.
They look happy.
I didn't expect them to like it so much.
Since they like it,
we'll paint another one next year.
We'll paint one every year.
Clear Mind's business
will get bigger and bigger.
There will be more and more people.
One painting can't fit everyone.
Don't be silly.
We can paint a large painting.
This wide. Or this wide.
It will fit everyone.
It will take a little longer.
-We will sit.
-It's good.
Painting brings us good luck.
I'm telling you.
You hung the painting well this year.
You will also hang
the next year's painting.
Let's talk about it next year.
It depends on my mood.
What do you mean by that?
-What's wrong?
-That won't do.
I'm taking you as a waiter at Clear Mind.
It's not like you'll not be at Clear Mind.
I'm just a waiter?
I should be a manager at worst.
I can't afford to pay a manager.
Money doesn't matter.
Ms. Su.
I want you to give me a job for life.
Look.
Zhang Jin looks much taller than me.
His hat is tall.
Look.
I'm handsome in the painting.
I'm tall and mighty.
The painting painted us well,
especially you and me.
It's nice.
Ninety-eight…
Fifty…
Ms. Su.
These are samples.
I put the rest in the backyard.
With these raw materials,
we can fill Mr. Kang's order.
And the rest can be made into jewelry.
Clear Mind's
glass crown and belt were sold out
as soon as they hit the shelves.
Clear Mind is finally in luck.
Ms. Su.
When I came back just now,
I found that the Zhenlang Pavilion
was not open.
It's not open?
Open the door.
Open up. There's big business coming.
Clear Mind wants to buy Zhenlang Pavilion
at a high price.
This is your last chance.
Who said we wanted
to sell Zhenlang Pavilion?
If you're not selling it,
why don't you open the door
and do business?
It has nothing to do with you.
Wait.
IS Zhenlang Pavilion for sale?
If you don't do business,
you'd better sell it to me.
Even if you don't sell it to me,
someone else will buy it.
You're wasting your shop.
This table is nice.
-We need a table.
-You…
Cui Shijiu.
Why are you hiding?
Tong.
Send them away.
Did you hear it? Get out.
I'm begging you.
If you're just looking
for a place to stay,
you should continue
to be the Cui's legitimate daughter
and rely on the Zheng family.
If you want to start all over again,
run Zhenlang Pavilion well.
Get out. Stop it.
Cui Shijiu, your time is running out.
Ms. Su, why do we always help her?
She deserves it.
Zhenlang Pavilion's situation
will affect our business.
Tell me.
Why does she get everything
she wants?
Why can't I get
what I want?
Am I wrong?
Or is it something I want wrong?
Zhenlang Pavilion.
All I did was to get you.
Now, I finally got you.
I own Zhenlang Pavilion.
But I'm alone.
Mother.
Father.
Wu.
I finally got Zhenlang Pavilion.
But I'm alone.
In that case,
I don't need you.
I don't want you.
I don't want Zhenlang Pavilion.
I don't want it.
I want them back.
I want my mother.
I want my father.
I want them back.
I don't want it.
The glass is transparent.
Ms. Su, our goods arrived.
Duanwu, have a look.
Are those raw materials?
These raw materials
are from the Kang royal family.
They must be good.
They are of good quality.
We can make good glassware.
Time is tight.
Should we hire some people to help you?
We have to train new recruits.
And they are not necessarily reliable.
It's okay.
We have Mr. Qin, a veteran expert.
We can finish it by working overtime.
Why didn't Mr. Qin come out?
The glass is good.
He'll be so happy to see it.
He didn't come today.
I sent Gaoshou to go to him.
Mr. Qin is usually the first to arrive.
Is he sick?
Gaoshou, where is Mr. Qin?
Where is he?
I asked you to go to him.
I did. His daughter wasn't at home.
And I didn't see him.
I thought he was here.
We're on a deadline. Where did he go?
I don't know.
Yunxiu.
Go to Mr. Zhang
and ask him to come to Clear Mind.
Mr. Qin left suddenly
without telling anyone.
It's weird.
Yingtao, stay in the shop.
Tell Mr. Yan about it when he gets back.
Gaoshou, come with me.
Ms. Su.
Why don't you wait for Mr. Yan?
Don't worry, Yingtao.
I'll go with Ms. Su.
What can you do?
I can do anything. Let's go, Ms. Su.
Let's go.
-Take good care of Ms. Su.
-Rest assured.
Why did Mr. Qin suddenly return
to his hometown?
Don't worry, Ms. Su.
This is the only way to Zizhou.
We'll catch up with him. Don't worry.
What do you want?
Let go of me.
Ms. Su, something is going on over there.
I'll check it out.
I'll be back in a minute.
Wait for me in the carriage.
Gaoshou!
-Wait here.
-Yes, ma'am.
Gaoshou!
Gaoshou. Gaoshou, wake up.
Su Muzhe.
You killed my two sons.
You made me, Zheng Shiyuan,
lose my offspring.
Today,
either you get down on your knees
and apologize to them
or…
I'll bury you here.
Zheng Shiyuan.
Don't pretend to be a good father.
You know how your two sons died.
The person
who should kneel is you, not me.
Drop the act.
You want my blood-stained pearl.
Right?
Su Muzhe.
You made my two sons
unable to enter the ancestral hall
after they died.
Do you know how sad I am?
You, give everything at Clear Mind to me
and get out of Yangzhou.
-Maybe I'll spare your life.
-You killed your sons.
It's you, Zheng Shiyuan.
You killed your sons.
You want my Clear Mind.
Dream on.
Master, the savior is coming.
Let go of me.
Let go of me!
Are you saying that she and Gaoshou
went to chase Mr. Qin?
Yes. Ms. Su said we couldn't delay.
So, they went to chase him.
She was too reckless.
What if they encounter bad people?
CLEAR MIND
They haven't come back yet?
-What took them so long?
-I don't know.
-I'll go find them.
-Don't rush.
Let's go to the glass shop first.
What if they're already back?
-Okay, let's go.
-Go.
-I'll go with you.
-Stay here and watch the shop.
Help!
Hello? Help!
-Where is your father?
-I'm looking for him, too.
Where did he go?
Neighbors said he went out in the morning
and said he was going back
to his hometown.
Go back to his hometown?
Is Mr. Qin a bait?
Zheng Shiyuan.
Mr. Zheng. Did you make it?
You startled me.
With your help,
Su Muzhe will die.
Where is the stuff?
I'm the only one in the world
who can tell if it's real.
It's just a blood-soaked jade bead.
It's unlucky.
Why do you want it?
Do you want to ruin our business?
The Zheng family made many mistakes.
You redeemed yourself
by finding the blood-stained pearl.
When can I meet the savior?
Wait.
Well.
I want to take you to a place.
We'll go to a place
where there are just the two of us.
When we get there,
I'm not Zheng Wu
and you're not Cui Shijiu.
We can live our own lives.
Wu.
I'd rather die
than let anyone hurt Cui Shijiu.
Shijiu…
Stay alive…
Zhuohua.
Your name is Cui Zhuohua.
You're not just Cui Shijiu.
Remember.
Wu, I'll pick myself up and live.
For you
and for myself.
Tong.
Lady Shijiu.
Go get Garuda.
Yes, I'll open the door for business.
I ask you to get Garuda.
Don't we open the door? Are you going to…?
Yes, I will get Garuda.
Help me do my hair.
Yes, ma'am.